Register of the Andrei Terent'evich Bel'chenko Papers, 1898-1962
Hoover Institution Archives
- Chinese Politics File, 1918-1949.; Boxes 16-22
  - Scrapbooks of clippings and notes on current events concerning China, France and U.S.S.R. Includes some diary entries
    - 1946 February 1-1947 April 18 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 1946 August 1-1947 July 24 (Folder 2)
  - Subject file
    - China--History--Clippings under the general heading "Komintern v Kitae," 1926-1939. Include materials on the role of M. M. Borodin in China, 1927, arrest and detention of his wife, raids on Soviet consulates and embassy in Peking, 1927, 1912-1949. (Folder 3)
    - China--Politics and Government--20th century. Decrees of the Chinese Emperor, Russian translations, 1908. (Folder 4)
    - Famines--China. Bulletins, clippings, reports, correspondence, on famines and floods, 1922-1932 (Folder 5)
    - Newspaper strike, Han-k'ou, China, 1927. Includes strike editions of foreign newspapers, and clippings relating to strike, 1927 March - April (Folder 6)
    - Trade-unions--China. Clippings and correspondence relating to labor unions and strikes, 1926 December-1927 March (Folder 7)
- Subject File, 1900-1947; Boxes 22-25
  Correspondence, official documents and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Cohn, A. Letter of recommendation by Bel'chenko and other characterization, 1938 January (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Dies, Martin, Translation of speech by Bel'chenko, 1951. (Folder 9)
  - Diplomatic and Consular Service, American--China. Circulars to all foreign consuls, 1927-1938 (Folder 10)
  - Diplomatic and Consular Service, British--China. Circular to all foreign consuls at Hankow, 1927 April 22 (Folder 11)
  - Hankow, China--History
    - Foreign Residents Association (Folder 12)
    - Municipal Bureau of the Special Administrative District No. 3 of Hankow, Report for the Year 1940 and Budget for the Year 1941 [Hankow (Folder 13)
    - Russian Concession. Administration
      - Electors - Statements
        - 1906-1919 (Box 23, Folder 1)
        - 1922-1923 (Folder 2)
      - Public Council
        - Annual budgets and financial reports
          - 1903-1920 (Folder 3)
          - 1920-1923 (Folder 4)
        - Minutes of meetings
          - 1915 (Folder 5)
          - 1916 (Folder 6)
          - 1917 (Folder 7)
          - 1920 (Folder 8)
          - 1921-1922 (Box 24, Folder 1)
          - 1923-1925 (Folder 2)
    - Special District Administration, Hankow, Report for the Year 1925 and Budget for the Year 1926 [Hankow (Folder 3)
    - Miscellany (Folder 4)
  - Korostovets, I. Ia., 1911 (Folder 5)
  - Litvinova, Elizaveta Nikolaevna (Folder 6)
  - Morison, V. A. (Folder 7)
  - Pick, Eugene (pseud.) (Folder 8)
  - Portuguese--China. Includes issues of Pela Patria Russians--China (Folder 9)
    - Hankow
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Pushkinskii komitet (Folder 11)
      - Rossiiskii emigrantskii komitet. Minutes of meetings, 1939-1945 (Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 13)
    - Legal cases
      - General - Arrests (Folder 14)
      - Bauman/Lonshak case, 1930 (Folder 15)
      - Berezin/Kuznetsova case. Includes correspondence relating to inheritance to be paid to relatives in USSR, 1926-1929 (Folder 16)
      - Feuerbach, George. Includes correspondence, affadavits and court certificates, 1918-1929 (Folder 17)
      - Lebedev, Dimitrii Antonovich, 1927-1929 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Malashkin. Estate administered by Bel'chenko), 1933 (Folder 2)
      - Rymsha, Nikolai Vikent'evich (Folder 3)
      - Samorukoff, Sergei Semenovich. Power of attorney, 1922 August 22 (Folder 4)
      - Tsentrosoiuz. Mainly relates to deportation of its representative A. A. Kosolapov (Folder 5)
    - Press. Includes Bel'chenko's typescript "O russkoi pechati v g. Khan'kou," and correspondence, clippings and biographical material (on Bel'chenko) collected by A. S. Loukashkin, 1949 February 19 (Folder 6)
    - Shanghai. Clippings, 1939-1940 (Folder 7)
    - Women. Includes correspondence with officials of League of Nations and report on situation of women and children in the Far East, 1934-1935 (Folder 8)
  - Russia. Ministerstvo inostrannykh del
    - Book entitled Spisok chinov Ministerstva Inostrannykh Del, St. Petersburg, 1913 (Folder 9)
    - Circulars, 1901-1902 (Folder 10)
  - Soviet Union (1924-1939)--Internal conditions. Typescripts and printed matter. Includes Informatsionnyi biulleten' (Paris, 1934-1937) (Folder 11)
  - Miscellany. Includes Japanese poster appearing on streets of Wuhan cities, propaganda materials in Russian, and other matter, 1941 December 8 (Folder 12)
- Photographs, 1938-1954 and undated; Box 26
  Fifteen photographs of Bel'chenko and others individually and in groups
  - Eight group photographs, mainly of Bel'chenko with other Russians in Hankow, Includes photographs of Consul P. S. Popov, pupils of Russian school in Hankow, Russian World War I veterans and members of the Hankow Russian Club (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Seven photographs of Bel'chenko and unidentified figures in Hankow and San Francisco, 1938-1954 and undated (Folder 2)
- Oversize File, 1944-1945 and undated; Box 26
  Section of diary (1944-1945) and one writing
  - Diaries, 1944 December 10-1945 October 30 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Writing entitled "Taina samoubiistva Ioffe," Typescript, n.d. (Oversize 4)